MICHAEL BADE Software Engineer



San Marcos, TX 78666



mbadedeveloper@gmail.com



225-287-3847



www.mbadedeveloper.com



Michael Bade



mbade1



@mbadedeveloper

MISSION

Full-stack engineer experienced with React, Ruby on Rails, and fluent in JavaScript, and Ruby. Excellent at independent and collaborative work with distributed teams.

With a background in the music industry, focused on technical mastery, project management, and client relations, with a record of delivering work on time. Writing code that matters, for the betterment of the world.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES

Ruby on Rails React/Redux Sinatra

LANGUAGES & TOOLS

JavaScript
HTML
CSS
Ruby
SQL
SQLite
Postgresql
Git
Heroku

PROJECTS

Trail Running Planner - Github | Live Site

The Trail Running Planner helps runners pack appropriately for trail runs.

- Implemented frontend with React/Redux for state management, working in conjunction with a Rails API backend.
- Secures user information by encrypting user registration in a Postgres database.

Vegan Camping Cookbook Collective - Github | Live Site

Designed for outdoor enthusiasts to create a cookbook of their favorite camping recipes.

- Developed an intuitive frontend with vanilla JavaScript.
- Designed a RESTful API and implemented a range of endpoints.
- Designed a relational database schema and deployed Postgres on the backend.

Doggo Play Date - Github | Live Site

An app that lets users to make doggo playdates in the Austin, TX area with Covid restrictions.

- Created a Rails MVC app, with OAuth as an easy, one-click solution for users to log in.
- Follows CRUD actions and RESTful conventions, along with ActiveRecord relationships in the backend.

Mileage Tracker - Github | Live Site

Created to help marathoners keep track of the mileage on their running shoes.

- Utilized an MVC Sinatra framework, for ease of flow from User to backend queries.
- Keeps users' information safe and secure with the bcrypt gem, and implementing Postgres in production.

EXPERIENCE

Heart Support Developer

Volunteer Developer on an international team.

Austin, Texas 09/2020 - 10/2020

- Joined a group of volunteer developers for a 6-week sprint in "writing code that matters." We connected users on Facebook who are suffering from depression to the Heart Support discourse channel and database.
- Implemented a method which uses Facebook's API, and registers each user in the Heart Support database.
- Worked on an international team with weekly standups, pair programming over Zoom, communicating on Slack, and meeting goals with Trello.

Jim Barnes Middle School

6th-8th Grade Choir Teacher

Seguin, Texas 08/2017 - 05/2020

St. John's Lutheran Church

6th-8th Grade Choir Teacher

San Antonio, Texas 08/2017 - 05/2020

Hudson Middle School

6th-8th Grade Choir Teacher

Sachse, Texas 08/2016 - 05/2017

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Stack Software Engineering Program

Remote 05/2020 - 10/2020

Louisiana State University

Master's Music, Vocal Performance (3.95 GPA) Bachelor's Music Education (3.55 GPA) Baton Rouge, LA 05/2016